Devesh Takoor

Full Stack Developer

Brisee Verdiere, Flacq | + 230 5288 6463 | <u>Email-address</u> <u>Github</u> |<u>LinkedIn</u>|

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer experienced in Python and JavaScript based programming with a background in STEM Learning, AeroModelling. Passionate musician and actor in short movies and sketches/skits. Possess strong skills in Critical Thinking and Problem Solving that help provide solutions to almost every problem during projects. Have the faculty to manage a team and with proper team distribution.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, JavaScript, Html, CSS, Flask, SQL, OOP, Augmented Reality, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, PHP(Laravel), VB.Net

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Real Time Telemetry Website - GitHub | Demo

This website is an API(Application Programming Interface) which allows us to communicate with other applications: to access data and interact with external software components, operating systems, or microservices. This webpage is mainly to connect my passion for robotics to web development. This API can later be used for many other tasks such as: Stock exchange, Managing profits/loss, Statistics.

- Used Arduino and MQTT-Broker to collect sensor data
- Used Javascript for an OTP(One Time Password) sent to email to confirm your account while signing up and also for displaying graphs.
- Databases were used to store user details and to display and upload products to be rented.
- CSS was used for animations.
- Python was used to run Flask and also for backend operations (check if accounts exist, check for correct hashed password, authentication, etc.)
- JSON was used while dealing with real time data

MauRent - GitHub | Demo

This website does not own anything, it just creates a connection between people who want to trade things & maximize their return on investment while buying assets. There is no after sale service, the website is only a display window.

- Used Javascript for an OTP(One Time Password) sent to email to confirm your account while signing up.
- Databases were used to store user details and to display and upload products to be rented.
- CSS was used for animations.
- Python was used to run Flask and also for backend operations (check if accounts exist, check for correct hashed password, etc.)
- Has WhatsApp included to deal directly with the lessor

StarDust Wedding Planner - GitHub | Demo

Planner that includes different services needed to plan a wedding.

- Used Local Storage to save the items in the cart.
- JSON in Javascript to display the products in all the pages.
- Javascript for the email system (this feature will send you all the products that you have ordered to your email).
- CSS for basic animations.

OTHER PROJECTS

iCCo (Intelligent Cap Collector)

The product is made to detect small caps which are often thrown and neglected while cleaning which still causes lots of pollution. The robot collects all the caps using an automated arm and then separates the plastic and metal caps using electromagnet that will be sent for recycling or reusing.

• Arduino, Raspberry Pi and Mblock Based project.

eSPR(Electronic Student Planno Reminder)

Students at secondary level often face two problems, one of them is that they forget to bring their copy books or books to school and the other is they tend to have a messy table which again leads to not finding their belongings on their table. The eSPR allows the student to have an organized table and also it tells them which subject they have the particular day so that they save up time in matching their timetables

Arduino based project.

Smart Dispenser

During the Covid-19 period lots of people were being infected by negligence, one of them was exposing too much person for works that could be done automatically, which is why I decided to do a sanitiser dispenser which could also check your temperature reading at lower prices as it was expenses to import at that time and also decreases 2 persons at work. The project was then modified later for ketchup, oil, etc dispenser by removing the temperature sensor.

Arduino based projects.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Operations - Robotics

Port Louis, Mauritius 05/2019 – 28/02/2023

First Global Mauritius (YUVA Mauritius)

Recruitments and Training of participants

• Guide the participants throughout the international competition

Software Engineer

Stratalis Ltd

Grand Baie, Mauritius 03/10/2022 – 28/02/2023

- Web Scraping
- Web browser extensions
- Website Automation
- Data Migration

Associate Software Engineer

Software Concepts Ltd

Debug clients Software

New web base(Php Laravel) products for client

Port Louis, Mauritius 01/05/2022 - 30/09/2022

Insurance Sales Agent

Afri Life Insurance

Flacq, Mauritius 07/2021 - 02/2022

Deal with Clients for the best insurance plans according to their budget

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development, Python program

.

Developers Institute, TLV Coding Bootcamp

10/2021 - 03/2022

Higher School Certificate

Professor Basdeo Bissoondoyal College (Boys)

Flacq, Mauritius 05/2021

LANGUAGES

English, French, Hindi, Bhojpuri - Fluent

/2021 - 0

Quatres Bornes, Mauritius